Kyle Gates

(503)702-5800 • gates.kyle@hotmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/kyle-a-gates/

Portfolio: https://gateskyle.github.io/Portfolio-In-React/#/

GitHub: https://github.com/gateskyle

Web developer focusing on teamwork and inclusivity. Recently earned a full-stack developer certificate from the University of Oregon, which developed skills in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Node, MySQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, Mongoose, and React. Previous schooling included Python, Ruby, and C++. As well as prior work experience to communicate clearly and work smoothly as a group.

Technical Skills

Programming languages: Intermediate knowledge of HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Node, MySQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, Mongoose, and React. Basic knowledge of Python, Ruby, and C++.

IDE: Visual Studio Code

OS Environment: Windows 7/10

Software Packages: Working knowledge of Microsoft Office (Word, PowerPoint, Outlook)

Computer Hardware: Built PC desktop computer system from components for programming and general use.

Projects:

Mood Ring | Github Link: https://bit.ly/35jj2cA | Live Link: https://bit.ly/2ROPtwx |

- A group project were a user can log in with a Google account and check their mood using facial recognition and receive remedies based on the mood, which is then saved to the user's profile and a chart is displayed based on their past moods.
- Was part of backend development team
- Technologies used were React, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Axios, Bootstrap, Express, If-env, MongoDB, Heroku, React-bootstrap, React-google-login, React-router-dom, Facial Recognition Technology and Live Webcam (both Facial Recognition and Webcam's links can be found on the github link).

DND Helper | Github Link: https://bit.ly/3wjgAz1 | Live Link: https://bit.ly/3wjgAz1 |

- This app is a step by step guide for players wanting to learn how to create a character for Dungeons and Dragons.
- Was part of backend development team
- Technologies used include: HTML, CSS, Google CSS Api, Express, MySQL2, and Sequelize.

Entertainment Lists | Github Link: https://bit.ly/2SyhTeu | Live Link: https://bit.ly/2SyhTeu |

- A group project in which the team created a website to access a database to receive and display information about books, movies, and video games using three different APIs.
- Was part of the backend development team
- The languages used were HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and JQuery.

Google Book Search | Github Link: https://bit.ly/3iPE76P | Live Link: https://bit.ly/3ggk6UX |

- A web page designed to find and save a book based off a user search
- Did both front and back end
- Technologies used were React, Bootstrap, Google Books API, and JavaScript

Education

Coding Bootcamp Certificate from University of Oregon

October 2020 – May 2020

Completed a course in front end (HTML, CSS, and JavaScript) and back end (Node, MySQL, and MongoDB) website development with individual and group projects.

Portland Community College, Rock Creek Campus 2018

September 2017 – December

Completed 38 credit hours toward associate's degree in web site development. Courses taken included HTML and C++, and required classes including Algebra, English, History, and Photography.

Employment

Fred Meyer

May-September 2018, September – December 2019

Fuel attendant responsible for providing excellent customer service and with a goal of customers leaving with a positive experience. Promoted to cashier responsible for providing accurate transactions and balancing till at the end of the shift. Additional responsibility of inspecting fuel storage tanks on a periodic basis for damage and corrosion and reporting issues to the maintenance team.

TekSystems

August 2021 – Current

• Contracted to Providence Health & Services from August 2021 to April 2022 as an Associate IS Support Technician assisting Caregivers and Providers with technical support of over 4000 applications (Including O365, Microsoft Azure Active Directory, and Citrix) and general computer troubleshooting (Windows 7, 10, 11, and Macintosh).

- Contracted to PeaceHealth for a two week (4/28/22 to 5/12/22) to support their Service Desk with Multi-Factor Authentication setup, as well as other technical support including Epic and general computer troubleshooting.
- Contracted to Power Engineers, Inc. from 6/6/22 to 2/17/23 as a Tier 1 Service Desk Technician and local IT for the Portland, Oregon office which included responsibilities such as handling tickets and answering phone calls to assist users with technical issues (which included programs such as Microsoft Office, Bluebeam, Autodesk), and providing support to local office, such as setting up workstations and providing hands on technical support.